<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>
  <RulePackDef>
    <defName>CA_CrossedLoreRecords</defName>
    <rulePack>
      <rulesStrings>
        <li>crossed_origin->The first confirmed Marked Virus cluster began as a blood-screening anomaly in a frontier hospital. Within four days the hospital staff were armed, organized, and hunting survivors by name.</li>
        <li>crossed_military_report->Military Report 17: Do not classify infected as undead. Subjects retain door use, weapon use, ambush planning, and speech. Treat every infected human as an armed combatant.</li>
        <li>crossed_survivor_journal->Survivor Journal: The worst part was the laughing. They remembered the hallways. They remembered the locks. They remembered us.</li>
        <li>crossed_audio_log->Audio Log C-44: Marked rash is most visible around the eyes and cheeks. Advanced cases show a dark red X pattern across the face, neck, and upper torso.</li>
        <li>crossed_progression->Medical Note: Most confirmed victims resolve quickly. A terminal case usually becomes one of the Marked Men or dies from viral collapse; rare slow infections remain lucid longer.</li>
        <li>crossed_timeline->Planetary Timeline: Exposure. Rapid onset. Psychosis. Death reanimation. Transformation. Organized raids. Settlement collapse. Alpha migration.</li>

        <li>crossed_dormant_research->Research Log 47-D: We identified a latent viral state in asymptomatic carriers. The pathogen integrates with host neural tissue without triggering immune response. Dormant carriers show no markers, no symptoms, and no behavioral deviation until activation.</li>
        <li>crossed_dormant_medical->Medical Incident Report: Case file 47-D-3. Colonist presented normal vitals, normal cognition, no viral markers. Activated on day 19 of observation. Transformed in 47 seconds. Killed three before containment. No prior indicators found in post-mortem review.</li>
        <li>crossed_dormant_survivor->Witness Statement: They ate with us. They slept in the bunk next to mine. They helped reinforce the barricades. When it happened, there was no warning. No fever. No rash. Just the change in their eyes and then the screaming.</li>
        <li>crossed_dormant_alpha_emergence->Field Report: Dormant Alpha activation produces immediate coordination in surrounding infected. Quarantine protocol revised: any carrier reaching transformation threshold triggers immediate zone lockdown. Alphas emerging from dormancy are priority-alpha threats.</li>
        <li>crossed_dormant_close_contact->Safety Bulletin: Dormancy does not reduce contagiousness. Carriers shed viral material at lower rates than active cases, but prolonged close contact carries measurable risk. Maintain standard exposure protocols for all personnel regardless of symptom presentation.</li>
      </rulesStrings>
    </rulePack>
  </RulePackDef>
</Defs>
