<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <CA_ModName>The Marked Men</CA_ModName>
  <CA_CrossVirusName>Marked Virus</CA_CrossVirusName>
  <CA_LoreBook_Title>The Marked Men</CA_LoreBook_Title>
  <CA_LoreBook_Opening>The Marked Virus did not raise the dead. It left people alive, clever, cruel, and organized enough to end worlds.</CA_LoreBook_Opening>
  <CA_LoreBook_ResearchNote>Field diagnostics identify a fast terminal pattern: most victims resolve quickly into either Marked Men transformation or viral collapse, while rare slow cases last longer.</CA_LoreBook_ResearchNote>
  <CA_MilitaryReport_01>Military Report 01: Infected subjects retain weapon use, speech, door operation, cover-seeking behavior, and group tactics. Do not approach as medical casualties.</CA_MilitaryReport_01>
  <CA_MilitaryReport_02>Military Report 02: Alphas coordinate nearby infected by sound, gesture, and remembered command structure. Remove Alpha units first whenever possible.</CA_MilitaryReport_02>
  <CA_SurvivorJournal_01>Survivor Journal: They did not forget us. That was the first lesson. The second was that they knew which doors we locked.</CA_SurvivorJournal_01>
  <CA_AudioLog_01>Audio Log C-44: Rash presentation forms a marked vascular pattern across the face and neck. Advanced cases glow red under certain scanner bands.</CA_AudioLog_01>
  <CA_PlanetaryTimeline>Medical timeline: contagious close-contact exposure, infected blood contamination, fast terminal progression, rare slow infection, uncommon immune survival, viral death risk, and Marked Men transformation.</CA_PlanetaryTimeline>

  <!-- Predatory Instincts System -->
  <CA_KillAnticipation_Label>kill anticipation</CA_KillAnticipation_Label>
  <CA_KillAnticipation_Desc>The predator's senses sharpen in the presence of prey. Reflexes quicken and focus intensifies with every hostile nearby.</CA_KillAnticipation_Desc>
  <CA_FreshKillSatisfaction_Label>satisfying kill</CA_FreshKillSatisfaction_Label>
  <CA_FreshKillSatisfaction_Desc>The rush of a clean kill. The hunt paid off.</CA_FreshKillSatisfaction_Desc>
  <CA_BloodthirstyCraving_Label>bloodthirsty craving</CA_BloodthirstyCraving_Label>
  <CA_BloodthirstyCraving_Desc>The hunger for violence grows. It has been too long since the last hunt.</CA_BloodthirstyCraving_Desc>
  <CA_OverwhelmingBloodlust_Label>overwhelming bloodlust</CA_OverwhelmingBloodlust_Label>
  <CA_OverwhelmingBloodlust_Desc>The battle consumed everything. There is only the kill.</CA_OverwhelmingBloodlust_Desc>
  <CA_PredatorPatience_Label>predator's patience</CA_PredatorPatience_Label>
  <CA_PredatorPatience_Desc>Watching. Waiting. The prey does not know it is already marked.</CA_PredatorPatience_Desc>
</LanguageData>
