<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <CA_ModName>The Marked Men</CA_ModName>
  <CA_CrossVirusName>Marked Virus</CA_CrossVirusName>
  <CA_LoreBook_Title>The Marked Men</CA_LoreBook_Title>
  <CA_LoreBook_Opening>The Marked Virus did not raise the dead. It left people alive, clever, cruel, and organized enough to end worlds.</CA_LoreBook_Opening>
  <CA_LoreBook_ResearchNote>Field diagnostics identify a fast terminal pattern: most victims resolve quickly into either Marked Men transformation or viral collapse, while rare slow cases last longer.</CA_LoreBook_ResearchNote>
  <CA_MilitaryReport_01>Military Report 01: Infected subjects retain weapon use, speech, door operation, cover-seeking behavior, and group tactics. Do not approach as medical casualties.</CA_MilitaryReport_01>
  <CA_MilitaryReport_02>Military Report 02: Alphas coordinate nearby infected by sound, gesture, and remembered command structure. Remove Alpha units first whenever possible.</CA_MilitaryReport_02>
  <CA_SurvivorJournal_01>Survivor Journal: They did not forget us. That was the first lesson. The second was that they knew which doors we locked.</CA_SurvivorJournal_01>
  <CA_AudioLog_01>Audio Log C-44: Rash presentation forms a marked vascular pattern across the face and neck. Advanced cases glow red under certain scanner bands.</CA_AudioLog_01>
  <CA_PlanetaryTimeline>Medical timeline: contagious close-contact exposure, infected blood contamination, fast terminal progression, rare slow infection, uncommon immune survival, viral death risk, and Marked Men transformation.</CA_PlanetaryTimeline>

  <!-- Predatory Instincts System -->
  <CA_KillAnticipation_Label>kill anticipation</CA_KillAnticipation_Label>
  <CA_KillAnticipation_Desc>The predator's senses sharpen in the presence of prey. Reflexes quicken and focus intensifies with every hostile nearby.</CA_KillAnticipation_Desc>
  <CA_FreshKillSatisfaction_Label>satisfying kill</CA_FreshKillSatisfaction_Label>
  <CA_FreshKillSatisfaction_Desc>The rush of a clean kill. The hunt paid off.</CA_FreshKillSatisfaction_Desc>
  <CA_BloodthirstyCraving_Label>bloodthirsty craving</CA_BloodthirstyCraving_Label>
  <CA_BloodthirstyCraving_Desc>The hunger for violence grows. It has been too long since the last hunt.</CA_BloodthirstyCraving_Desc>
  <CA_OverwhelmingBloodlust_Label>overwhelming bloodlust</CA_OverwhelmingBloodlust_Label>
  <CA_OverwhelmingBloodlust_Desc>The battle consumed everything. There is only the kill.</CA_OverwhelmingBloodlust_Desc>
  <CA_PredatorPatience_Label>predator's patience</CA_PredatorPatience_Label>
  <CA_PredatorPatience_Desc>Watching. Waiting. The prey does not know it is already marked.</CA_PredatorPatience_Desc>

  <!-- Lost Survivor System -->
  <CA_LostSurvivor_Title>Lost survivor found</CA_LostSurvivor_Title>
  <CA_LostSurvivor_Desc>A disoriented survivor has wandered to the colony's edge. They claim to have been separated from their group days ago and have been traveling alone since. Something about their story feels incomplete, but they seem grateful for shelter.</CA_LostSurvivor_Desc>
  <CA_LostSurvivor_Accept>Accept them</CA_LostSurvivor_Accept>
  <CA_LostSurvivor_Reject>Send away</CA_LostSurvivor_Reject>
  <CA_LostSurvivor_Betrayal_Label>Dormant infection activated!</CA_LostSurvivor_Betrayal_Label>
  <CA_LostSurvivor_Betrayal_Text>The dormant Marked Virus infection in {PAWN_labelShort} has suddenly activated! The colonist you took in was carrying the pathogen without visible symptoms — until now.

{PAWN_labelShort} transforms before your eyes, joining the Marked Men. No warning. No chance to prepare. Just the terrible realization that the threat was already inside.</CA_LostSurvivor_Betrayal_Text>
  <CA_DormantMark_Label>dormant mark</CA_DormantMark_Label>
  <CA_DormantMark_Desc>A latent Marked Virus infection that has not yet activated. The host shows no symptoms and carries the infection without visible signs.</CA_DormantMark_Desc>

  <!-- Betrayal Thoughts -->
  <CA_BetrayedByColonist_Label>betrayed by colonist</CA_BetrayedByColonist_Label>
  <CA_BetrayedByColonist_Desc>Someone I trusted was carrying the Marked Virus. They were one of us until they weren't.</CA_BetrayedByColonist_Desc>
  <CA_BetrayedByColonistSocial_Label>betrayed by</CA_BetrayedByColonistSocial_Label>
  <CA_LovedOneTurned_Label>loved one transformed</CA_LovedOneTurned_Label>
  <CA_LovedOneTurned_Desc>A lover, spouse, or close friend was taken by the Marked Virus. What was left behind wore their face but was not them anymore.</CA_LovedOneTurned_Desc>
  <CA_SuspiciousOfColonists_Label>suspicious of colonists</CA_SuspiciousOfColonists_Label>
  <CA_SuspiciousOfColonists_Desc>If one of them was carrying the infection without knowing, any of them could be.</CA_SuspiciousOfColonists_Desc>
  <CA_MercifulKill_Label>merciful execution</CA_MercifulKill_Label>
  <CA_MercifulKill_Desc>I put down a colonist before they could turn. It was the right call, but that does not make it easier.</CA_MercifulKill_Desc>

  <!-- Survivor Armor -->
  <CA_SurvivorArmor_Label>survivor armor</CA_SurvivorArmor_Label>
  <CA_SurvivorArmor_Desc>A set of reinforced armor assembled from scavenged materials. Uneven plates, patched fabric, and improvised padding offer decent protection against the Marked, though the fit is far from uniform.</CA_SurvivorArmor_Desc>
</LanguageData>
